Francis R. Valeo Map Collection
Geography & Map Division, Library of Congress
Francis R. Valeo Map Collection comprises twenty-six road maps for the period 1954-1980 (bulk 1973-1974), and no date, donated by Francis R. Valeo. The maps cover mainly East Asia, specifically Japan, Hong Kong, and Macau. 1954-1980 (bulk 1973-1974)
G7800 coll .V3 Valeo
Francis R. Valeo
Twenty-six maps: some color; various sizes
Geography & Map Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The Francis R. Valeo Map Collection comprises twenty-six maps for the period 1954-1980, and no date, and cover mainly East Asia, specifically Japan, Hong Kong, and Macau
Provenance
The materials in the Francis R. Valeo map collection were donated to the Library of Congress by Francis R. Valeo
Additional Guides
Francis R. Valeo papers, 1916-1987
Transfers
Maps Transferred from the Manuscript Division, Library of Congress, where they form part of the Francis R. Valeo Papers
Access and Restrictions
The Francis R. Valeo Map collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Geography & Map Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Francis R. Valleo (1916-2006) was an East Asia specialist in the Legislative Reference Service of the Library of Congress, a foreign affairs advisor to Senate Majority Leader Mike Mansfield, secretary of the Senate, and a consultant specializing in Chinese-Asian affairs.
Scope and Content Note
The Francis R. Valeo Map collection spans the years 1954-1980, with the bulk of the materials concentrated in the period 1973-1974. Coverage consists primarily of East Asia, specifically Japan, Hong Kong, and Macau
Arrangement of the Collection
The Francis R. Valeo Map collection collection is organized in a single series.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Valeo, Francis R. (Francis Ralph), 1916-2006, collector.
Places
Far East--Maps.; Hong Kong (China)--Maps.; Japan--Maps.; Macau (China)--Maps.
Form/Genre
Maps.
Container List
- Francis R. Valeo Map Collection
  Forms part of the Francis R. Valeo Papers, Manuscript Division
  - PBS Interconnection System, 1973, United States; Public Broadcasting System (Box-item 1/1)
  - Washington, D.C. and Vicinity, Washington, D.C.; Washington Convention &Visitors Bureau (Box-item 1/2)
  - South America, 1960, South America; National Geographic Society (Box-item 1/3)
  - Mapa Geografico Brasil Norte e Leste Ofercido pela Varig, Brazil; Seccao de Cartografia do LIVR DO GLOBO (Box-item 1/4)
  - Brussels, Belgium; Beheer Voorlichingscentrum (Box-item 1/5)
  - Ente Provinciale per il Turismo -- Roma, Italy; Ente Provinciale per il Turismo (Box-item 1/6)
  - [Cairo, Egypt], Egypt (Box-item 1/7)
  - Moscow Illustrated Map, Russia; Intourist Head Office (Box-item 1/8)
  - Tourist Map of Japan, 1974, Japan; Japan National Tourist Organization (Box-item 1/9)
  - Tourist Map of Tokyo, 1976, Japan; Japan National Tourist Organization (Box-item 1/10)
  - Map of Tokyo & Surrounding District, 1954, Japan; Japan Travel Bureau (Box-item 1/11)
  - Okinawa and Ryukyu Islands, Okinawa; Caltex (Box-item 1/12)
  - Guide Map of Sapporo City, Japan (Box-item 1/13)
  - Mobilgas Road Map: Hong Kong and the New Territories, 1961, Hong Kong; General Drafting Co., Inc. (Box-item 1/14)
  - Sightseeing Map of Hong Kong, Hong Kong; Chase Advertising, Ltd. (Box-item 1/15)
  - A.O.A. Map Sheet of Tsimhatsui, Kowloon Peninsula, 1974, Hong Kong; A.O.A. Ltd. (Box-item 1/16)
  - A.O.A. Map Sheet of Wanchai, Hong Kong Island, 1974, Hong Kong; A.O.A. Ltd. (Box-item 1/17)
  - A.O.A. Map of British Crown Colony of Hong Kong, 1974, Hong Kong; A.O.A. Ltd. (Box-item 1/18)
  - A.O.A. "A to Z" [History and Description of Hong Kong], Hong Kong; A.O.A. Ltd. (Box-item 1/19)
  - A.O.A. Map Sheet of Hong Kong Urban Areas, Public Transportation, 1974, Hong Kong; A.O.A. Ltd. (Box-item 1/20)
  - A.O.A. Small Map Sheet of Macau, Macau; A.O.A. Ltd. (Box-item 1/21)
  - Hong Kong and Macau, 1970, Macau and Hong Kong (Box-item 1/22)
  - A.O.A. Map Sheet of Portuguese Province of Macau, 1974, Macau; A.O.A. Ltd. (Box-item 1/23)
  - Macau, A.O.A. Ltd. (Box-item 1/24)
  - Thailand, 1980, Thailand (Box-item 1/25)
  - Ceylon, 1963, Ceylon; Government Tourist Bureau (Box-item 1/26)